Guide to the Eastern Parkway Coalition records 2007.016
Brooklyn Historical Society
Eastern Parkway Coalition records
1952-2007
1970-2007
Brooklyn Historical Society
Eastern Parkway Coalition.
2007.016
12.5 Linear Feet in nine record cartons, six rolled document cases, one oversize flat box, and one loose rolled item
The collection is composed of the records of the Eastern Parkway Coalition, dating from 1952 to 2007 (bulk dates, 1970-2007). These records are primarily composed of subject files, which document many issues which affected the Crown Heights and Prospect Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn. These issues include community gardens, housing/tenant rights, mass transit, summer youth programs, drug abuse, environmentalism, mental health, public parks, and urban renewal. In addition to subject files, the records include a series of plans and maps for the reconstruction of Eastern Parkway and other streets in the area.
Scope and Contents note
The collection is composed of the records of the Eastern Parkway Coalition, dating from 1952 to 2007 (bulk dates, 1970-2007). These records are primarily composed of subject files, which document many issues which affected the Crown Heights and Prospect Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn. These issues include include community gardens, housing/tenant rights, mass transit, summer youth programs, drug abuse, environmentalism, mental health, public parks, and urban renewal. In addition to subject files, the records include a series of plans and maps for the reconstruction of Eastern Parkway and other streets in the area.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open to users without restriction.
Arrangement
The records are organized into two series:
Series 1: Subject files, 1952-2007
Series 2: Plans and maps, 1973-1988
Historical note
The Eastern Parkway Coalition (EPC) is a community organization based in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Established in the 1970s, the organization ran summer youth programs, many of which focused on community improvement and gardening. The group established a community garden atop the Franklin Avenue Shuttle subway station at the Botanic Garden/Eastern Parkway/Union Street. In 1989, New York City Transit Police demolished the community garden with the intention of clearing the land for a parking lot. The garden was later reestablished due to community outrage. As of 2011, the EPC continues to sponsor community gardening programs in the Crown Heights and surrounding neighborhoods of Brooklyn.
Related Materials
Antonia Denis collection, 1948–1983 (1992.021)
Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation Oral History collection, 2007-2008 (2008.030)
West Indian Carnival Documentation Project records, 1993-1996 (2010.019)
Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation publication and photograph collection, 1968–2007 (ARC.124)
Brooklyn neighborhood associations and civic organizations publications, 1881-2010 (ARC.167)
Junior League of Brooklyn records, 1910-2002 (ARC.304)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Constance Lesold, 2007.
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Audiocassettes; Community activists -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Clippings (information artifacts); Haitian Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County; African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Gateway National Recreation Area (N.J. and N.Y.); Mental health services -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Newsletters; Local transit |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Maps; Posters; Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.); Parks |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Photographs; Tenants' associations |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Urban beautification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; West Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Streets |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Design and construction; Subway stations |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Subways |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Drug addiction |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Dutch elm disease |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Eastern Parkway (New York, N.Y.); Environmentalism |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Community gardens |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Correspondence; Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Reports; Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.); Eastern Parkway Coalition Garden (New York, N.Y.); Blueprints (reprographic copies); Eastern Parkway Coalition.; Community Board No. 9 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).; Community Board No. 8 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).; Brooklyn Tenants Union Incorporated (New York, N.Y.).; Brooklyn Museum; Brooklyn Botanic Garden; Kingsboro Psychiatric Center; City University of New York. Medgar Evers College; West Indian American Day Carnival Parade (Brooklyn, N.Y.).; Greens/Green Party USA; Parks Council (New York, N.Y.).; New York (N.Y.). Dept. of Parks and Recreation.; New York (State). Metropolitan Transit Authority.; Lesold, Constance; Lesold, Helmuth
- Series 1: Subject files, 1952-2007; 1970-2007; 21233; 11 Linear Feet in ten record cartons and one oversize flat box
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains subject files of the Eastern Parkway Coalition, and includes documents dating from 1952 to 2007.
  The files were maintained by Constance Lesold, who was also an active member of other community groups, such as Community Board 8/9, the Brooklyn Tenants Union, and local block associations. Files related to those other organizations appear frequently in the series.
  The series documents several issues relating to the Crown Heights and Prospect Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn from the 1970s to the early 2000s. These issues include community gardens, housing/tenant rights, mass transit, summer youth programs, drug abuse, environmentalism, mental health, public parks, the Haitian community, and urban renewal.
  Community gardens are especially well represented in the files, especially the Franklin Avenue Shuttle Garden, which was demolished by the Metropolitan Transportation Authority (MTA) in 1989. Controversy over the Brooklyn Botanic Garden charging entrance fees is also addressed in the series.
  Cultural affairs are also featured in the series, especially the Brooklyn Museum, the Brooklyn Public Library, and the New Muse.
  The files are primarily composed of flyers, publications, correspondence, memoranda, and clippings. A small amount of files include photographs, slides, negatives, and audio cassettes.
  Arrangement
  The files in this series were recieved in a disorganized state and are not arranged in any particular order. Unfoldered documents were placed in folders and labeled by the processing archivist. The titles for these folders have been enclosed in brackets.
  - [Clippings, correspondence, and banner], 1981-1989; 21415 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [MTA correspondence], 1988; 21414 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Eastern Parkway news articles and publications, 1973-1980; 21413 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Urban Park Rangers, 1979-1980; 21412 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Tree Tips, 1979-1984; 21411 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - [Hand drawn garden map], circa 1980s; 21410 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Air and noise pollution, 1974-1978; 21409 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Growing herbs and vegetables, 1975-1982; 21408 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Container gardening, 1977; 21407 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Wild plants, 1978; 21406 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - House plants and poisonous plants, 1977-1980; 21405 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Endangered species, birds, butterflies, zoos, dogs, and mouse care, 1980-1983; 21404 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Planetaria, 1952-1983; 21403 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Timed materials, flowers, insects and diseases, and tools, 1979-1981; 21402 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Watering tips, soil and compost, ground covers and vines, and berries (strawberries), 1979-1981; 21401 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Eastern Parkway complaint form, circa 1980; 21400 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Other groups' on the parkway events, 1978-1980; 21399 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Municipal Arts Society, 1982, 1999; 21398 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Squibb and Van Vorhees Parks, 1980-1981; 21397 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Community gardens, local group purchasing energy, horticultural society, and NY street tree consortium, 1977-1984; 21396 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Gateway, 1979-1984; 21395 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Al-Karim School, 274 St. John's Place and Grand Army Plaza, EPC and Community Board 8: Utica Avenue and EP substation, 1980 Boro budget meetings, 1979-1980; 21394 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    General
    Crown Heights housing and landlord-tenant complaints
  - Community Board 8, 1978-1984, 1996; 21393 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - [Flyers, publications, clippings], 1978-1980; 21392 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - [Clippings], 1978-1980; 21391 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - [Flyers, publications, clippings], 1977-2006; 21390 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - [Earth Day and unidentified event photographs], circa 2000; 21389 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - [Lincoln Place and Eastern Parkway united neighborhood block association], 1976-1977; 21388 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Obituaries, 1983-1991; 21387 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - [Mount Prospect Park], 1988; 21386 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden fees / protests, 2002; 21385 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden and Prospect Park (1 of 2), 1980-2002; 21384 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden and Prospect Park (2 of 2), 1980-2002; 21383 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Park Slope and Brooklyn Greens, 1998-1999; 21382 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - [New York City Committee on Health / American Lung Association], 1998; 21381 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Pediatric Asthma Center
  - [New York City Department of Environmental Protection meetings], 2006-2007; 21380 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Herbicides and Pesticides, 1999-2006; 21379 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pesticides and West Nile Virus (1 of 2), 1998-2006; 21378 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Green Party
  - Pesticides and West Nile Virus (2 of 2), 1998-2006; 21377 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - [Pesticides] (1 of 2), 2000-2001; 21376 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - [Pesticides] (2 of 2), 2000-2001; 21375 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Black Music Association, 1979; 21374 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - New Muse, 1973-1982; 21373 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - [Lincoln Place United Block Association and New Muse], 1974-1992; 21372 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Includes material related to Arthur Miller and Nostrand Avenue Community Commerce Association
  - [Lincoln Place United Block Association and New Muse], 1976-1980; 21371 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Includes photographs
  - Maps, 1976; 21370 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    District maps, Jimmy Carter, Woodrow Lewis, local politics, Medgar Evers College
  - Community Board 8 - Structure and membership, 1978-1981; 21369 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - CD V hearings material, 1978-1979; 21368 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Community development grants, Community Board 8, New Muse, Arthur Miller, Nostrand Avenue Community Commerce Association
  - Community Board 8 press release, 1983; 21367 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Programs and proposals by various organizations, 1971-1973; 21366 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Drug abuse prevention
  - Drug abuse prevention, 1972-1975; 21365 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    77th Precinct Community Council, Crown Heights Youth Center
  - [Eastern Parkway Coalition, Brooklyn Tenants Union, The Muse, and other organizations], 1977-1979, 1989; 21364 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    St. John's Recreation Center, Haitian American Day Care Center
  - Phoenix Center correspondence, 1970-1973, 1981; 21363 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - [League of Women Voters of the City of New York election booklets], 1978-1993; 21362 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - [Brooklyn Botanic Garden - Dutch Elm Disease], 1978-1982; 21361 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - [Eastern Parkway petition form, New Muse exhibition, 1977 Calendar of the Board of Estimate, and police clippings], 1977-1992; 21360 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Library kiosks - Brooklyn Tenants Union, 1978-1980; 21359 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    SNAP award, Jacob K. Javits correspondence
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - Meetings attended by board and staff members, 1977-1979; 21358 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Various Crown Heights community groups, including The East (Jitu Weusi)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - Publicity, 1979; 21357 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Includes reports on rent strikes
  - [Children's issues], 1978-1979; 21356 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - [Newsletters, publications, clippings], 1973-1979; 21355 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Community groups and gardening
  - [Flyers, publications, clippings], 1999-2007; 21354 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Brooklyn Botanic Garden fees
  - Summer Youth Program (1 of 2), 1979; 21353 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Summer Youth Program (2 of 2), 1979; 21352 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Summer Youth Program - Garden time sheets, 1979; 21351 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - [Flyers, newsletters, clippings], 1981-1989; 21350 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Franklin Avenue Shuttle and garden; includes photographs
  - Eastern Parkway, 1978-1981; 21349 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Community Board 8
  - Eastern Parkway Area Committee, 1977; 21348 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Street tree pruning and maintenance course, 1979; 21347 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Eastern Parkway Coalition - Notice of meetings and events on Parkway, 1978-1987; 21346 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Eastern Parkway Coalition - Garden correspondence, 1978-1989; 21345 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    1979 Garden lease
  - Eastern Parkway Coalition - Planning ideas, 1977-1981; 21344 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Bills and receipts, 1979-1984; 21343 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Community Board 8 - Parks Committee, 1979-1985; 21342 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Eastern Parkway Coalition stationary, circa 1979; 21341 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - [Garden files], 1978-1989; 21340 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Copy of Franklin Avenue Shuttle Community Garden destruction petition
  - Eastern Parkway Coalition applications, circa 1982; 21339 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - [Community Board 8 - Environmental fairs, apartheid protest, and other events], 1984-1986; 21338 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Merchant appeals, 1980; 21337 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Dutch Elm trees pamphlets and survey, 1973-1982; 21336 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Operation Greenthumb, 1979-1986; 21335 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    1984-1985 Garden lease
  - Eastern Parkway Coalition - Correspondence and newsletters, 1979-1984; 21334 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Dutch Elms and Franklin Avenue Shuttle
  - Eastern Parkway Coalition - Meetings attended, 1982-1985; 21333 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Franklin Avenue Shuttle Community Garden, 1979-1984; 21332 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Franklin Avenue Shuttle Community Garden - Summer programs, 1982-1983; 21331 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - West Indian Day Carnival, 1979-1983; 21330 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Black Spectrum Theater and other Coalition groups, 1978-1979; 21329 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - [Crown Heights Board of Community Affairs], 1971-1979; 21328 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Grant Square, 1980-1984; 21327 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Grants information, 1981; 21326 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Trust for Public Land and Neighborhood Open Space Coalition, 1979; 21325 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1978-1981; 21324 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Parks Council, 1978-1984; 21323 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Includes photograph
  - Magnolia Tree Earth Center, 1975-1985; 21322 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Council on the Environment, 1974-1983; 21321 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Greenmarket
  - Environmental Defense Fund and Environmental Action Coalition, 1974, circa 1980; 21320 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Weeksville, Cornell Extension, Green Guerilla, NY State Department of Environmental Conservation, Maps of area, Drug Abuse Prevention Proposal Committee, St. John's C.C. - CB 8 - Parks Committee, 1973-1984; 21319 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Children's projects, 1977; 21318 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Other landmark groups, 1978-1984; 21317 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - [Crown Heights - Area Maintenance Program], 1972-1976; 21316 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Crown Heights newsletters, 1971-1977; 21315 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - [New York City Community Planning Districts], 1973-1977; 21314 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Registered Democrats, 1976-1978; 21313 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - [Comprehensive Employment and Training Act (CETA)], 1977-1978; 21312 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    New Muse, Brooklyn Tenants Union, Brooklyn Renaissance Coalition for Jobs
  - [Clippings and flyers], 1969-1983; 21311 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Beware of Elms in Thunder audio recordings, 1980; 21310 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Two audio cassette tapes, also includes Gail Guillet, NYC Landmarks Commission, NPR, Bilingual Education Conference, and universal identity card
  - Artists of the Eastern Parkway Coalition - Beware of Elms in Thunder sign, circa 1980; 21309 (Oversize OS-30)
  - Kingsboro and Mental Health (1 of 3), 1976-1981; 21308 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Brooklyn Tenants Union, Brooklyn Association for Mental Health
  - Kingsboro and Mental Health (2 of 3), 1976-1981; 21307 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Kingsboro and Mental Health (3 of 3), 1976-1981; 21306 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - [Brooklyn Tenants Union - Rent strikes], 1966-1986; 21305 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Recent housing and CD materials, 1981; 21304 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - Summer Youth Program, 1979; 21303 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Notes of Executive Board meetings and membership, 1978-1979; 21302 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Brooklyn Tenants Union
  - Incorporation papers, by-laws, and finances, 1977-1979; 21301 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fire, Brooklyn Community Council and Black Community Congress of Central Brooklyn, Brooklyn Tenants Union, [CETA applicants], [Albany bus trip], Personnel information, BTU - Other current projects, People's Housing Network, census tracts, The East, 1974-1991; 21300 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Old membership list, current material on Coalition, proposals writing, Campaign for Human Development, proposals, [SYEP time sheets], Progress Reports, circa 1976-1980; 21299 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - [Calendar of the Board of Estimate of the City of New York], 1977; 21298 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union stamp, circa 1978; 21297 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - [New York City Housing Authority - Welcome to your Home], circa 1978; 21296 (Oversize OS-30)
    Children's activity book
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden - Fee issues (1 of 3), 1993-2002; 21295 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden - Fee issues (2 of 3), 1993-2002; 21294 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden - Fee issues (3 of 3), 1993-2002; 21293 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Lesold - Community Board 8 Parks Committee correspondence, 1973-2002; 21292 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Includes garden photographs
  - [Magnolia Tree Earth Center], 1990-1991, 1998; 21291 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - [Flyers, newsletters, clippings], 1997-2005; 21290 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Medgar Evers College, Parks Department budget, Marty Markowitz photograph, community gardens, McCarren Park, and St. Johns Recreation Center
  - [Calendar of the Board of Estimate of the City of New York and census], 1978; 21289 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn 2000 - State of the Borough, 21288 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - [Youth Programs] (1 of 2), 1980-1984; 21287 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - [Youth Programs] (2 of 2), 1980-1984; 21286 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - [Brooklyn Botanic Garden and Haitians], 1986-2006; 21285 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - [Brooklyn Botanic Garden and Haitians], 1986-2006; 21284 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - [Brooklyn Botanic Garden and Haitians], 1986-2006; 21283 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Includes other Crown Heights organizations
  - [Eastern Parkway Coalition exhibition at New Muse and photographs], 1980; 21282 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Includes tree planting ceremony at the Franklin Avenue Shuttle Community Garden and other garden photographs/slides/negatives
  - [Haitians], 1987-1990; 21281 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - [Brooklyn Botanic Garden and Haitians], 1986-1990; 21280 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Haitian-American Citizens for Action financial aid, 1987; 21279 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - [Brooklyn Botanic Garden and other group publications], 1981-1999; 21278 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - [Eastern Parkway Coalition photographs], 1978-1980; 21277 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - [Eastern Parkway Coalition flyers, memoranda, and tree records], 1979-1996; 21276 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - [Visits to Haiti], 1996-1997; 21275 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - [Visit to Haiti photographs], 1996; 21274 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - [Eastern Parkway Coalition, Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Haitian groups, and other organtizations] (1 of 2), 1980-2006; 21273 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Includes photographs of EPL garden party photographs
  - [Eastern Parkway Coalition, Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Haitian groups, and other organtizations] (2 of 2), 1980-2006; 21272 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - [Grand Jury Repression], 1978; 21271 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Jackson Point Du Jour, 1975-1978; 21270 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Haitian Coalition on AIDS cassette tape, 1988; 21269 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Haiti Projects in Partnership, 1998-1999; 21268 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - [Haiti] (1 of 2), 1998-2005; 21267 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - [Haiti] (2 of 2), 1998-2005; 21266 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Gateway, 1978-1979; 21265 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program, 1979; 21264 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Includes garden sketches and plans
  - Community Gardens, 1999; 21263 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Community Gardens, 1998-2002; 21262 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Community Gardens, 1999; 21261 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Community Gardens, 1999; 21260 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Prospect Place Garden petition, 1983; 21259 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Eastern Parkway Area Committee - Summer Youth Program - Sanitation, 1978; 21258 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - [Museum/Art censorship], 1999; 21257 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - [Community Gardens and Parks], 1996-2006; 21256 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - [Brooklyn - music and tourism], 1979, 2007; 21255 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Franklin Avenue Shuttle Garden, 1979-2001; 21254 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Includes photographs and garden plans
  - Underfunding of Black organizations, 1976-1978; 21253 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Greenthumb NYC, 2002; 21252 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1978-1983; 21251 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Includes Community Board District 8 city program and project review
  - [Franklin Avenue Shuttle and other subway issues], 1981-1991; 21250 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - First Annual Conference on NYC Public Transit, 1981-1982; 21249 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - [Community Board 8 committees - Parks and NYC public transit], 1981-1994; 21248 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - MTA - Rules of Behavior, 1989-1992; 21247 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Franklin Avenue Shuttle, 1981-1983; 21246 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - [Subway clippings], 1986; 21245 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - MTA - Hearing rules, 1990; 21244 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Summer bus service to Gateway, 1982-1989; 21243 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - [Franklin Avenue Shuttle and other subway issues], 1986-1993; 21242 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - MTA Board, 1990-1991; 21241 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Community Board 9 - Transportation committee, 1983-1990; 21240 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Franklin Avenue Shuttle, 1981-1982; 21239 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - [Brooklyn Public Library, Brooklyn Museum, Oliver Leeds, citywide strike], 1981-1994; 21238 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook items, 1987; 21237 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Includes material relating to Haitians and other Crown Heights community issues; includes photographs
  - Transportation reports, 1980s; 21236 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Transportation reports, 1980s; 21235 (Box 9, Folder -)
    Includes Franklin Avenue Shuttle reports
  - Eastern Parkway Coalition proclamation, 1989; 21234 (Oversize OS-30)
- Series 2: Plans and maps, 1973-1988; 21416; 1.5 Linear Feet in six rolled document cases, one oversize flat box, and one loose rolled item